{
  "chapter": 3,
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "Utility model of computing is beneficial for",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Users of computing",
        "Vendors of computing",
        "Both a and b",
        "None"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "The term ‘cloud computing’ was first presented in its current meaning in the year of",
      "incorrect_answers": ["1999", "2006", "2008", "2010"],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is/are feature(s) of utility service model?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Metering",
        "Billing",
        "On-demand service availability",
        "All of these "
      ],
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following companies was first to successfully adopt utility computing model for enterprises?",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Amazon", "Salesforce.com", "IBM", "Google"],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Heterogeneous software applications communicate over the internet using",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "HTML",
        "Message passing",
        "Web services",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Presently, the web services are categorized as",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "SOAP & REST",
        "SOAP & RPC",
        "REST & RMI",
        "REST & CORBA"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "REST is considered as the light-weight alternative of SOAP since it can avoid",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "the use of global identifier for resources",
        "the use of JSON for message passing",
        "the use of XML for message passing",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Use of REST-compliant web services results in longer development time than using of SOAP-based web services in cloud computing development. This statement is",
      "incorrect_answers": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "REST is a/an",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Message communication protocol",
        "Architectural style",
        "Web architecture",
        "Cloud type"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is not a benefit of cloud computing?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Low initial investment",
        "Fixed cost of computing",
        "Access through internet",
        "High-performance computing"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is not considered as an inherent nature of cloud computing?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Flexibility",
        "Elasticity",
        "Scalability",
        "Portability"
      ],
      "answer": 4
    }
  ]
}
